Register of the Herbert Hoover subject collection, 1895-2006
Hoover Institution Archives
- HOOVER-WILSON CORRESPONDENCE, 1914-1920 (Box 6-9, 367)
  - Wilson to Hoover. Calls attention to need of cooperation of packing trade; emphasizes they must follow directions of Food Administration., February 19, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Domestic transportation of foodstuffs., February 19, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., February 19, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Congressional investigation of the Grain Division of the Food Administration., February 20, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Food Administration's relation with packers., February 21, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Approves of investigation by F.W. Taussig of the grain division of Food Administration, if he has time., February 21, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. March program of Allied shipments., February 26, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson (not sent)., February 27, 1918
  - Hoover to Tumulty., February 28, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Mr. Spreckels' contract for purchase of Cuban sugar., March 1, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Recommendation of William S. Tyler as Federal Food Administrator for New Jersey., March 2, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Sends Hoover copy of letter that is addressed to Bernard Baruch, asking Baruch to accept chairmanship of War Industries Board; asks Hoover's cooperation with Board when occasion arises., March 4, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Selection of Mr. Baruch to head War Industries Board., March 5, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Agrees with Hoover that Spreckels presents no sufficient reasons why he cannot join the other sugar refineries., March 5, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Recommendation of W.S. Tyler as Federal Food Administrator for New Jersey., March 6, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Wheat supplies in the United States., March 7, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Possibility of a 15,000,000 bushel per month shortage of wheat for the United States; believes the country should sacrifice and use substitutes., March 8, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to T.W. Brahany., March 15, 1918
  - T.W. Brahany to Lewis Strauss., March 15, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Asks whether it would be convenient for Hoover to meet at White House with McAdoo, Baruch, Hurley, McCormick, and Garfield., March 16, 1918
  - Miles to Lewis Strauss., March 18, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Appreciation of note of March 16., March 19, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., March 20, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Asks for suggestion of answer to enclosed telegram about relief of prices on livestock for cattle feeders., March 21, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., March 21, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Draft of reply to Col. Hudson's telegram., March 22, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Cereal supplies during the next three months., March 22, 1918
  - Tumulty to Lewis Strauss., March 23, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Thanks for letter of March 22; realizes seriousness of situation about further relief of Allies, but believes they have to do as best they can in the situation., March 25, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., March 26, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. J.H. Barnes' memorandum on the effect of a higher guaranteed wheat price., March 26, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Commission to study the meat problem., March 26, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Meat industry position., March 26, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Western Grain Exchange., March 26, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Thanks for Julius Barnes' letter; thinks he is right and notes he presents his case with all its force., March 27, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Does not think he is qualified to judge on merits of arrangements proposed by Western Grain Exchange; leaves decision in Hoover's hands., March 27, 1918
  - Tumulty to Lewis Strauss., March 27, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., March 27, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Appointment of Food Administration member to Inter-Allied Council., March 27, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Glad to confirm appointment of J.H. Skinner as representative of Food Administration on Inter-Allied Council., March 28, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Telegram from Bartlett Frazier Co., March 28, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Has read enclosed letter on meat industry in country and believes it is all right to publish it; approves of plan for appointment of commission., March 29, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Appointment of a commission to consider meat policy., April 1, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Asks Hoover if he could replace F.W. Taussig on the investigation of the milling division of Food Administration; his other duties on Price Fixing Committee conflict with the inquiry in the milling division., April 2, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Asks for Hoover's advice as to answer to enclosed telegram from Morris & Co., April 2, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Recommendation of C.B. Ames as Food Administrator for Oklahoma., April 4, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Sends enclosed report on Federal Trade Commission food investigation of flour milling and flour jobbing., April 4, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Food Administration staff changes., April 4, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Telegram from Morris & Co., April 4, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Appreciation for copy of report of the Federal Trade Commission on flour milling., April 6, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Request for shipping for the Belgian Relief Commission., April 8, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., April 8, 1918
  - Hoover to Tumulty., April 9, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., April 10, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Appointment of a State Food Administrator for Virginia., April 12, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. States that Virginia Governor is evidently indignant about appointment of Lee as Food Administrator for Virginia; does not want to reply before informing Hoover of situation., April 12, 1918
  - Hoover to Tumulty., April 13, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. License regulations governing salt-water fishermen., April 20, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Recommendation of H.B. Sproul as Food Administrator for Virginia., April 23, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Proclamation on licensing., May 3, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Recommendation of F.H. Brooks as Food Administrator for Vermont., May 6, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., May 7, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., May 8, 1918
  - Presidential order reporting organization to be known as Food Purchase Board., May 8, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Comments on the transfer of government employees from each department to newer departments, thus weakening the older agencies., May 8, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to T.W. Brahany., May 8, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., May 9, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson., May 11, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., May 13, 1918
  - Hoover to Tumulty., May 13, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., May 14, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., May 14, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Shipping for Belgian relief., May 17, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Has examined enclosed report and before passing judgment on it asks Hoover to read letter by Mr. Colver., May 20, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Shipping for Belgian relief., May 20, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Government operation of packing plant., May 21, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Note regarding Mr. J.S. Williams., May 25, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Elimination of the War Industries' Price Fixing Board., May 27, 1918
  - Hoover to Tumulty., May 27, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Has received Hoover's letter of May 21, on revised report to members of Committee on Packing Industry; approves of conclusions in report., May 28, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., June 1, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., June 3, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., June 3, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Use of grain for brewing., June 5, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Thanks for sending letter from Senator Morris Sheppard; is willing, if Sheppard is, to make it public., June 5, 1918
  - Draft for President on Coordination of the Activities of the Governments of the U.S., Great Britain, France, and Italy., June 12, 1918.
  - Hoover to Wilson. Allied relations to the Food Administration., June 13, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Shipping shortage., June 13, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., June 14, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Has received monthly reports on activities of Food Administration; thinks arrangements made by Hoover satisfactory., June 14, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Believes Hoover's trip to France, England, and Italy will result in creating a better situation concerning food supplies., June 14, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Monthly report on Food Administration., June 14, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Executive order for consideration., June 15, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., June 15, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Sugar industry., June 15, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Believes Hoover's plan right one and will be prepared to supply $5,000,000 capital if $50,000,000 appropriation Sundry Civil Bill goes through., June 17, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., June 17, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Notes that at Wednesday conference with Hoover it was provisionally agreed that because of the necessity of conserving coal, the production of malt products should stop; in view of this, sees no reason for issuing amended regulations enclosed; wants to know if regulations represent earlier conclusion., June 18, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Wilson., June 18, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Executive order on government guarantee on wheat., June 20, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., June 21, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Use of grain for brewing., June 21, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., June 21, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., June 24, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Curtailment of non-war industries., June 26, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Telegram of Mr. W.W. Brauer., June 26, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Recommendation of P.R. Bradley as Food Administrator for Alaska., June 29, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Suggests study of world harvest supplies, establishment of executive meeting for jute and hemp, establishment of a universal bread of 20 percent other cereals than wheat., June 29, 1918
  - Report of the U.S. Food Administrator to the President., July 1, 1918 (Box 8)
  - Hoover to Wilson. Curtailment of non-war industries., July 2, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Proclamation guaranteeing the price of wheat., July 4, 1918
  - C.L. Swem to Hoover., July 6, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Recommendation that Mr. Glasgow attend conference., July 8, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Price guarantee on wheat., July 8, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Request for more building space., July 8, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Committee of heads of departments of the Food Administration., July 8, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Reply to Sen. Simmons on tax legislation., July 8, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Acknowledgment of Trade Commission report on regulation of packers' profits., July 8, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. On the report of the Trade Commission upon the effect of the Food Administration's regulation of the packers' profits., July 8, 1918
  - Wilson to Edgar Rickard. Tells of letter received from Hoover about office space for Grain Corporation and Sugar Equalization Board; is quite willing to authorize space but believes money can be saved by contacting Col. Ridley, Supt. of Public Buildings and Grounds, and also the Chief Assessor of the District Administration., July 9, 1918
  - Presidential statement on the formation of a sugar equalization board by the Food Administration., July 9, 1918
  - L.A. Small to Edgar Rickard., July 10, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Profiteering by five big packers., July 11, 1918
  - Hoover to Tumulty., July 11, 1918
  - Edgar Rickard to Wilson., July 11, 1918
  - Hoover to Edgar Rickard., July 11, 1918
  - Tumulty to Edgar Rickard., July 12, 1918
  - Wilson to Edgar Rickard. Wants Rickard's advice on matter referred to in letter from Jouett Shouse, on how much money is needed, and would it be permissible to advance sum from national security and defense fund., July 16, 1918
  - Edgar Rickard to Wilson., July 18, 1918
  - Edgar Rickard to Tumulty., July 26, 1918
  - Undated note from C.L. Swem.
  - Edgar Rickard to Wilson., July 26, 1918
  - Wilson to Edgar Rickard. Agrees with Secretary of Agriculture David Franklin Houston that it is wise to fix price of wheat, and wants Rickard to arrange early meetings., July 26, 1918
  - A.S. Burleson to Wilson., August 2, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Agreement between Hoover and the Food Ministers of Great Britain, France, and Italy., August 3, 1918
  - Wilson to Edgar Rickard. Sends Rickard enclosed letter from Benant S. Keck, which comments favorably on Wilson's veto of the minimum wheat price bill., August 6, 1918
  - Wilson to Edgar Rickard. Senator Morris Sheppard has sent enclosed telegram from cattle raisers; wants Rickard to either answer it or advise him about the situation., August 10, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Guaranteed price for wheat., August 10, 1918
  - Tumulty to Edgar Rickard., August 12, 1918
  - Edgar Rickard to Wilson., August 13, 1918
  - Edgar Rickard to Wilson., August 13, 1918
  - Wilson to Edgar Rickard. Appreciates importance of consulting Hoover about suggestions of Federal Trade Commission with regard to packers; hopes to defer decision until Hoover's return., August 13, 1918
  - Edgar Rickard to Wilson., August 14, 1918
  - Memorandum for Hoover together with reports on guaranteed price for wheat., August 15, 1918
  - Edgar Rickard to Wilson., August 15, 1918
  - Edgar Rickard to Tumulty., August 16, 1918
  - L. Trammell to Wilson., August 20, 1918
  - Memorandum for the President., August 23, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to the White House enclosing Inter-Allied Food Control agreement., August 24, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., August 26, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Guaranteed price for 1919 wheat., August 26, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Enclosing memorandum on guaranteed price for wheat., August 26, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Coordination of economic effort in Europe., August 27, 1918
  - Note from the White House to Hoover., August 27, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Guarantee price of wheat., August 27, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., August 28, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Appreciates number of considerations urged by Hoover for coordination of economic effort in Europe among the four nations and will keep them in mind during negotiations., August 28, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Sends volume that might furnish helpful information on sugar situation., August 29, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Sale of Cuban sugar to the United States., August 29, 1918
  - R. Forster to Hoover., August 30, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Executive Order guaranteeing wheat price., August 30, 1918
  - Lee Trammell to Wilson., August 30, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Appreciation for book., August 31, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Approves of conclusions and plans on Cuban sugar that Hoover has presented in his letter of August 29., September 2, 1918
  - Proclamation fixing guaranteed price for wheat., September 2, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. States power of agencies to commandeer material has resulted in conflict; the power to commandeer should not be exercised without first consulting Chairman of War Industries Board., September 3, 1918
  - Hoover to R. Forster., September 3, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Legal question involving Food Administration purchases., September 4, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Thanks for letter on purchase of grains for export by Grain Corporation., September 5, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Thanks for letter on "commandeering business.", September 6, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Coordination of effort with the War Industries Board., September 6, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Chicago packers problem., September 6, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Report of Food Administration., September 7, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Selective service deferments for Food Administration personnel., September 9, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Effect of Food Administration regulations on the packers., September 9, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., September 9, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Thanks for letter from Armour and Co. to Hoover, September 6, about packers' financial position; Wilson does not trust their information., September 10, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Thinks Hoover mistaken about draft exemptions; states new regulations take burden of claiming exemption off individual and put it upon employer or superior., September 10, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Wants Hoover to "read, ponder, and inwardly digest" enclosed letter on beef trade., September 10, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Recording his observations on the recommendations of the Federal Trade Commission with regard to the five large packing firms., September 11, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., September 11, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Transfer of part of Food Administration outside the district., September 12, 1918
  - B.M. Baruch to Wilson., September 12, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Proclamation regarding the brewing industry., September 13, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Beef supplies for the Navy., September 14, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Trade Commission's report on the packers., September 16, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., September 17, 1918
  - Hoover to Tumulty., September 18, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Recommendation of J.P. Cotton as chief representative in Europe., September 18, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Recommendations for representatives on the commodity committees in London, Paris, and Rome., September 18, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Curtailment of rampant business abuses., September 18, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., September 18, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., September 18, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Knows little about J.P. Cotton, but accepts Hoover's judgment about substituting Cotton for J.H. Skinner., September 19, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Is interested in bill by Frank B. Kellogg and thinks ideas in it are worth considering; hopes someone will redraft bill in conformity with recent legislation., September 20, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Has read enclosed letter about Federal Trade Commission report and suggests it perhaps would not be wise to publish., September 20, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Does not know anything about Merrill, Platt, and Walcott -- men recommended by Hoover to assist J.B. Cotton; willing to accept Hoover's judgment about them provided they are in no sense politicians., September 20, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Food support for Allies., September 21, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., September 24, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., September 25, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Failure of farmers to find a market for wheat., September 25, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Stabilization of the price of hogs., September 26, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Manufacture of malt liquor., September 30, 1918
  - Hoover to Tumulty., September 30, 1918
  - Hoover to Tumulty., October 4, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Selective service deferments for Food Administration personnel., October 4, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to M.C. Latta., October 4, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., October 5, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Expenses of representatives abroad., October 5, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Recommendation of W.H. Maltbie as Food Administrator for Maryland., October 7, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Mr. McAdoo's proposal to advance $50,000,000 to Brazil., October 7, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Authority of the Food Administrator., October 12, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Purchase of food by government agencies., October 12, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., October 16, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Food Administration budget for 1919., October 16, 1918
  - Hoover to Tumulty., October 17, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Price indices for food., October 17, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., October 18, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Conventions in Washington., October 19, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Relief of Belgium during occupation and rehabilitation., October 21, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Consideration of the postwar situation in food and opposing international control of world distribution., October 24, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Relief in Belgium., October 26, 1918
  - Tumulty to Hoover., October 31, 1918
  - Hoover to Tumulty., November 1, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. German shipment of Belgian coal out of Belgium., November 2, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. International control of distribution of food, raw materials, and ships., November 4, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Appreciation for Hoover's support., November 4, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Survey of the food supplies available in the world in case of an early peace., November 4, 1918
  - Wilson to Hoover. Believes the Commission for the Relief of Belgium should continue to be only agency for the government of the United States in continuing relief work in Belgium., November 7, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Letter enclosing dispatches to Mr. Cotton on the world's food and shipping supplies., November 7, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. On the question of feeding the liberated peoples of Austria, Serbia, Bulgaria, Turkey, etc., November 9, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Enlarging function of Belgian relief., November 9, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Letter enclosing cables from England suggesting a joint inter-Allied pool for distributing the world supply of wheat., November 11, 1918
  - Woodrow Wilson. Speech to State Food Administrators at White House., November 12, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Memorandum agreed upon by Baker, Hurley, and Hoover on European relief., November 12, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Executive Order delegating authority to Edgar Rickard to act in Hoover's place., November 13, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to Tumulty., November 14, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Food situation in Europe., November 14, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Letter enclosing cables which were sent to Mr. Cotton., November 14, 1918
  - Tumulty to Lewis Strauss., November 15, 1918
  - Tumulty to Edgar Rickard., November 16, 1918
  - Tumulty to Edgar Rickard., November 18, 1918
  - Edgar Rickard to Tumulty., November 19, 1918
  - Edgar Rickard to Tumulty., November 20, 1918
  - Tumulty to Edgar Rickard., November 27, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Memorandum on economic effects of blockade., December 10, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Relief for Yugoslavia and the use of Army personnel., December 16, 1918
  - G.F. Close to Hoover., December 18, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Letter on the question of reopening of brewing in the United States., December 19, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Suggestion for a joint statement by the four associated governments on bolshevism in Germany., December 20, 1918
  - G.F. Close to Hoover., December 21, 1918
  - Lewis Strauss to G.F. Close., December 23, 1918
  - Hoover to Wilson. Request for approval of extension of the operations of the Grain Corporation (rough draft only)., December 23, 1918
  - G.F. Close to Lewis Strauss., December 24, 1918
  - Wilson to William McAdoo. Food situation in Europe., January 1, 1919
  - Memorandum from Hoover. European blockade., January 1, 1919
  - Memorandum from Hoover. World food situation., January 2, 1919
  - Hoover to Wilson. Request for signature on proclamation rescinding certain food licenses., January 7, 1919
  - G.F. Close to Hoover., January 7, 1919
  - Lewis Strauss to G.F. Close., January 7, 1919
  - Hoover to Wilson. Withdrawal of Allied buying orders., January 8, 1919
  - Wilson to William McAdoo. Approves of $5,000,000 advance to Romania which Norman H. Davis has suggested to McAdoo; also urges Treasury to aid in disposal of surplus food products., January 9, 1919
  - Wilson to Hoover. Confirms Hoover's appointment as Director General of Relief in Europe; also appointment as representative of U.S. Government upon Council of Associated Governments., January 11, 1919
  - Edith Penham to Hoover., January 11, 1919
  - Hoover to Wilson. Letter enclosing minutes of the Supreme Council of Supply and Relief., January 12, 1919